Guide to the Walter Francis White and Poppy Cannon Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1921-1958; Series II; 7.09 linear feet (18 boxes)
  - Walter White
    - Broadcasts
      - Interview with Averell Harriman for WLIB, notes and transcript, typescript, 1954 May 24 (Box 25, Folder 251)
      - Interview with Senator Irving Ives for WLIB, draft for introduction, typescript, 1953 May 6 (Box 25, Folder 252)
      - Senator John Sparkman of Alabama as Democratic Vice-Presidential Nominee for WLIB, draft, typescript carbon, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 253)
      - Spingarn Medal awarded posthumously to Harry T. Moore for NBC, draft, typescript, corrected, 1952 June 29 (Box 25, Folder 254)
      - Statement on the Supreme Court decision on school segregation, draft, typescript, corrected, 1954 May 17 (Box 25, Folder 255)
      - Topics for discussion with Judge Francis E. Rivers for WLIB, draft, typescript and typescript carbon, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 256)
    - Short Stories
      - "April Fool", draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 25, Folder 257)
      - "Fame", draft, typescript, undated (Box 25, Folder 258)
      - Untitled, outline, holograph, undated (Box 25, Folder 259)
    - Book Reviews
      - Correspondence, 1931-1950, undated (Box 25, Folder 260)
      - Drafts, holograph, typescript, and typescript carbon, 1933-1949 (Box 25, Folder 261-263)
    - Other Writings
      - "Court Action and Other Means of Achieving Racial Integration in Education", draft, typescript, undated (Box 25, Folder 264)
        Transcript of panel discussion with Lester B. Granger, Oliver W. Hill, Herman H. Long, Ruth A. Morton, and John J. O'Conner
      - Desegregation in schools, press release, draft, typescript, 1954 December 15 (Box 25, Folder 265)
        Accompanied by memorandum to the N.A.A.C.P. board by Gloster B. Current on discrimination in Mississippi, dated 1954 December 13
      - "Industrial Memorandum", draft, typescript, undated (Box 25, Folder 266)
      - Inter-American Conference for Democracy and Freedom, draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1950 May (Box 25, Folder 267)
      - Poetry, drafts, typescript, undated (Box 25, Folder 268)
        Includes poems "Polish Mother", "Tinsel Moon", "The Drowning of Li-Po", Salesman", "Legs", "Lonely Things", "Ash Under Cedar", "La Vida Nueva", "Impiety", and "Ballad of Water"
      - "The Rapist", playscript draft, typescript, undated (Box 25, Folder 269)
      - "Round the World Town Meeting of the Air", draft, typescript, undated (Box 25, Folder 270)
      - "Suggested Program of Study and Action on the Radical Problem as it Affects International Relations and Foreign Attitudes Towards the United States", draft, typescript, 1953 October (Box 25, Folder 271)
      - "Testimony before Resolutions Committee, Democratic National Convention", draft, typescript, 1952 July 17 (Box 25, Folder 272)
      - Unidentified notes and writing fragments, undated (Box 26, Folder 273-281)
    - Writings of Others
      - Current, Gloster B., "We Shall Not Be Moved", draft, typescript, corrected, 1954 December 12 (Box 27, Folder 282)
      - David, John A., editor, Untitled Study, drafts, typescript, 1954 November 2 (Box 27, Folder 283-287)
        Includes reports by Franz B. Gross, Frank M. Snowden, and Ruth Sloan
      - Dean, John P. and Alex Rosen, "Intergroup Relations: A Manual for the Practitioner", draft, typescript, 1954 October 27 (Box 27, Folder 288-289)
      - Forsberg, Ruth, "New York's Interracial Ambassordor [sic]", draft, typescript, undated (Box 27, Folder 290)
      - Mason, Peter, "The Fire in the Flint: A Drama in Three Acts", typescript carbon, 1929 August (Box 27, Folder 291)
        See also: Dramatization, typescript, corrected.
      - National Citizens Commission for the Public Schools, "Financing Public Education in the Decade Ahead", draft, typescript, circa 1954 (Box 28, Folder 292)
      - Overton, Grant, "Remarks regarding 'The Fire in the Flint' at Library", transcript, typescript, 1924 November 6 (Box 28, Folder 293)
      - "Russian Propaganda on Race in America", draft, typescript, undated (Box 28, Folder 294)
      - White, Cynthia Cannon, Poem to Walter White and Poppy Cannon, draft, holograph, undated (Box 28, Folder 295)
      - White, William Lindsay, "Lost Boundaries: A Drama of Real Life", playscript, typescript, 1949 February 21 (Box 28, Folder 296)
      - Zangrande, Robert Lewis, "The Efforts of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People to Secure Passage of a Federal anti-Lynching Law, 1920-1940", abstract, typescript, photocopy, undated (Box 28, Folder 297)
  - Poppy Cannon
    The subseries is organized under the following headings: Major Works, Articles, Other Writings, and Writings of Others.
    - Major Works
      - A Gentle Knight
        - Draft, part I, holograph, corrected, Before 1958 (Box 29, Folder 298)
        - Draft, parts III-IV, typescript carbon, corrected, Before 1958 (Box 29, Folder 299-301)
        - Draft, parts II-IV, typescript carbon, corrected, Before 1958 (Box 29, Folder 302-304)
        - Draft, incomplete, leaves only on which changes were made, typescript, Before 1958 (Box 29, Folder 305)
        - Draft, setting typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, Before 1958 (Box 29, Folder 306-309)
        - Draft, including fragments and notes, holograph, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, Before 1958 (Box 30, Folder 310-312)
        - Draft, chapters I-III, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, Before 1958 (Box 30, Folder 313-314)
        - Draft, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected and holograph outline of chapters, Before 1958 (Box 30, Folder 315-317)
        - Draft, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, Before 1958 (Box 31, Folder 318-320)
        - Draft, parts I-II, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, Before 1958 (Box 31, Folder 321)
        - Publicity, 1956 (Box 31, Folder 322)
    - Articles
      - "Black Magic Cook Book", draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 32, Folder 323)
      - "Eleanor Roosevelt and the Race Problem", galley proof, Negro Digest, undated
      - "Foods and Songs of the Virgin Islands", draft, typescript, corrected, 1951 (Box 32, Folder 324)
      - "Guide to the Bride on Buying Food", draft, typescript, undated (Box 32, Folder 325)
      - Haiti writings
        - Publicity materials and related correspondence, 1951-1955 (Box 32, Folder 326-333)
          Includes news releases and drafts of Haitian guide book and of Highlights on Haiti
        - Haiti Today articles, drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected and related correspondence, 1953-1954, undated (Box 32, Folder 334-342)
      - "Lady Molly of Jamaica"
        - Drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 33, Folder 343)
        - Galley proofs, Negro Digest, undated
      - On the Presidential Campaign of 1956, draft, typescript, corrected and related material (Box 33, Folder 344)
      - On the Racial Situation in Detroit, draft, typescript carbon, undated (Box 33, Folder 345)
      - "A Question of Color", draft, typescript, undated (Box 33, Folder 346)
      - "What is She Really Like... Josephine Baker?", draft, typescript and background material, undated (Box 33, Folder 347)
      - "Who Is Colored and What Does Being Colored Mean?", outline and drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, undated
        See: "Who Is Colored and What Does Being Colored Mean?", outline and drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, box 24, folder 235.
        Written with Walter White
    - Other Writings
      - "Down with Realism: Long Live Reality", address given at the commencement of Oakwood School, Poughkeepsie, New York, drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, 1955 June 12 (Box 33, Folder 348)
      - Poems, drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, 1946-1947 (Box 33, Folder 349)
        See also: Poems, box 11, folder 82.
        Written for advertising while a consultant to Maxon, Inc. for the H.J. Heinz Company
      - "Puerto Rico Pineapple Film", script for narration of a publicity film on Puerto Rico, draft, typescript, undated (Box 33, Folder 350)
      - West Indies Poems, undated (Box 33, Folder 351)
    - Writings of Others
      - Dupuy, C.M., "Memorandum Concerning the Affairs in Haiti Since the American Occupation", circa 1930 (Box 33, Folder 352)
      - "Memorandum of the Service Technique de L'Agriculture et de L'Enseignement Professionnel", undated (Box 33, Folder 353)
      - Munro, Dana, "Memorandum Regarding the American Personnel Employed in the Public Works Service in Haiti", 1930 (Box 33, Folder 354)
      - Thoby, Perceval, "Memorandum on the So-Called Renewal of the Treaty of September 16, 1915 between the United States and Haiti", 1930 March 1 (Box 33, Folder 355)
- National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (N.A.A.C.P.), 1949-1954; Series III; 0.21 linear feet (1 box)
  The series contains memoranda, news releases, reports and correspondence documenting Walter White's work as the Secretary of the N.A.A.C.P. and spans the dates 1949 to 1954. N.A.A.C.P. related material is also located in the Correspondence series.
  - Memoranda, news releases, and reports, 1949-1954 (Box 34, Folder 356)
  - Correspondence, 1949-1952 (Box 34, Folder 357-358)
- Other Papers, 1929-1955, undated; Series IV; 1.04 linear feet (3 boxes)
  The series spans the dates 1929 to 1955 and contains personal papers (such as notebooks and financial records) and objects.
  - Walter White
    - Notebooks, 1930, undated (Box 35, Folder 359-363)
    - Appointment diaries, 1929-1955 (Box 36, Folder 364-370)
    - Wallets and contents, 1937-1953, undated (Box 36, Folder 371)
    - Financial records, 1948-1955 (Box 37, Folder 372)
    - Certificates (including certificate of death), 1946-1955 (Box 37, Folder 373)
    - Resolution from the State of New York expressing sympathy on Walter White's death, 1955
    - Money belt, undated (Box 37, Folder 374-381)
      Includes thirty-three bills which were formerly taped together into a single belt
    - Portrait of Walter White by Aaron Douglas, undated
      Pastel on paper, 73.5 x 58.1 inches
    - Caricature of White by Covarrubias, undated (Box 37, Folder 381a)
    - Plaques, 1944-1953, undated
      Contains five plaques awarded to Walter White from the Jackson Heights Lodge and Chapter for B'nai B'rith; Great Neck, Manhasset, Port Washington Branch of the N.A.A.C.P.; The Pyramid Club; Atlanta Branch of the N.A.A.C.P.; and the National Committee for Fair Playing in Bowling.
    - Walking stick, undated
      13 x .5 x .5 inches
    - Printed ephemera, 1935-1955 (Box 45)
      Contains newspaper clippings and a copy of The English Journal (March 1935) with White's article "The Negro on the American Stage."
    - Newspaper clipping regarding White's death and funeral, Chicago Defender, 1955 April 2
  - Poppy Cannon
    - Resume, undated (Box 37, Folder 382)
    - Guest book from Walter White's funeral, 1955 (Box 37, Folder 383)
- Photographs, circa 1910-1955; Series V; 0.42; (1 box)
  The series is organized into three subseries: Candid Portraits and Snapshots of Walter White and Poppy Cannon; Formal Portraits of Walter White; and Portraits of Others Inscribed to Walter White.
  The series includes formal portraits and snapshots of Walter White and Poppy Cannon. The series also includes photographs of White's and Cannon's families and friends. Many of the photographs were used in publications such as the N.A.A.C.P. Bulletin and Ebony.
  - Candid Portraits and Snapshots of Walter White and Poppy Cannon
    - White while student at Atlanta University and with his parents, circa 1910-1920 (Box 43, Folder 450)
    - White while war correspondent, 1943-1945 (Box 43, Folder 451)
    - White with James Weldon Johnson and Grace Nail Johnson at their home "Five Acres" in Great Barrington, Massachusetts, Before 1938 (Box 43, Folder 452)
    - White with military personnel, circa 1940-1948 (Box 43, Folder 453)
      Includes photographs of White with Tuskegee Airmen Lemuel R. Custis and Charles B. Hall and General Duff in Germany (1948 September 28).
    - White with Harry S. Truman and others, circa 1945-1950 (Box 43, Folder 454)
    - White and others at N.A.A.C.P. Rally in Washington, D.C., 1947 June 29 (Box 43, Folder 455)
    - White and Cannon at Adlai Steveson Rally, 1952 (Box 43, Folder 456)
    - White and others with Jawaharlal Nehru, circa 1950 (Box 43, Folder 457)
    - White receiving honorary degrees, undated (Box 43, Folder 458)
    - White with Leah Gladys Powell and their children Jane White and Walter Carl Darrow White, circa 1945 (Box 43, Folder 459)
    - White and Cannon in Haiti, circa 1953 (Box 43, Folder 460-463)
      Includes photographs of Paul Eugène Magloire
    - White and Cannon, circa 1950 (Box 43, Folder 464)
      Proofs for Ebony article
    - White and Cannon with Cynthia Cannon, Claudia Cannon, and other family members, circa 1950 (Box 43, Folder 465)
    - White with various people, undated (Box 43, Folder 466)
    - White at unidentified event, circa 1940-1950 (Box 43, Folder 467-468)
      Includes photographs of White with Robert C. Weaver and others
    - Snapshots of Cannon, Cynthia Cannon, Claudia Cannon, and others removed from Cynthia Cannon's scrapbook, circa 1940-1950 (Box 43, Folder 469-475)
    - Snapshots from various travels (including Trinidad and Puerto Rico), circa 1940-1950 (Box 43, Folder 476)
    - White's funeral, 1955 (Box 43, Folder 477-478)
    - Cannon publicizing How Far the Promised Land?, circa 1955 (Box 43, Folder 479)
    - Snapshots of unidentified sculpture of soldier, undated (Box 43, Folder 480)
  - Formal Portraits of Walter White
    - Early portraits of White at graduation and as Secretary for N.A.A.C.P., circa 1916-1925 (Box 43, Folder 481)
    - As war correspondent, circa 1943- 1945 (Box 43, Folder 482)
    - Publicity portraits for W. Colston Leigh, Inc., circa 1943-1950 (Box 43, Folder 483-485)
    - Publicity portraits of White in conversation, undated (Box 43, Folder 486)
      Contact prints
  - Portraits of Others Inscribed to Walter White
    - Black, Hugo L., 1944 October 26
    - Burrell, J. Mercer and others, undated
    - Charles, J., 1949 (Box 43, Folder 487)
    - Crump, Walter Gray, undated
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D. and others, circa 1940
    - Hastie, William, undated (Box 43, Folder 488)
    - Holman, Libby, undated (Box 43, Folder 489)
    - Horka, George A., undated (Box 43, Folder 490)
    - Johnson, J. Rosamond, undated (Box 43, Folder 491)
    - Lee, John C.H. and Jock Lawrence, 1944 February
    - McBride, Mary Margaret, undated (Box 43, Folder 492)
    - Meany, George, undated
    - Murphy, Frank, undated (Box 43, Folder 493)
    - Neilson, W.A., undated (Box 43, Folder 494)
    - Reuther, Walter P., undated
    - Wagner, Robert, undated (Box 43, Folder 495)
    - Williams, Robert, undated (Box 43, Folder 496)
    - White, W.A., 1938 (Box 43, Folder 497)
    - Wright, Louis Tompkins, undated
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 43, Folder 498)
- Oversize, 6.36 linear feet (4 boxes)
  - The Fire in the Flint, galley proofs, corrected (Series II), Before 1924 (Box Bsd, folder 384)
  - Flight, galley proofs, corrected (Series II), Before 1926 (Box Bsd, folder 385)
  - Flight, page proofs, corrected (Series II), Before 1926 (Box Bsd, folder 386)
  - Rope and Faggot: A Biography of Judge Lynch, page proofs, corrected (Series II), circa 1928 (Box Bsd, folder 387)
  - Book reviews, correspondence (Series II), 1931-1950, undated (Box 38, Folder 388)
  - "Eleanor Roosevelt and the Race Problem", galley proof, Negro Digest (Series II), undated (Box 38, Folder 389)
  - "Lady Molly of Jamaica", Galley proofs, Negro Digest (Series II), undated (Box 38, Folder 390)
  - Certificates (including certificate of death) (Series IV), 1946-1955 (Box 38, Folder 391)
  - Resolution from the State of New York expressing sympathy on Walter White's death (Series IV), 1955 (Box 38, Folder 392)
  - Portrait of Walter White by Aaron Douglas (Series IV), undated (Box Art, Folder 391a)
  - Plaques (Series IV), 1944-1953, undated (Box 41–42)
  - Walking stick (Series IV), undated (Box 42, Folder 392a)
  - White while student at Atlanta University and with his parents (Series V), circa 1910-1920 (Box 44, Folder 499)
  - White while war correspondent (Series V), 1943-1945 (Box 44, Folder 500)
  - White with various people (Series V), undated (Box 44, Folder 501)
  - Early portraits of White at graduation and as Secretary for N.A.A.C.P. (Series V), circa 1916-1925 (Box 44, Folder 502)
  - Publicity portraits of White in conversation (Series V), undated (Box 44, Folder 503)
  - Black, Hugo L. (Series V), 1944 October 26 (Box 44, Folder 504)
  - Burrell, J. Mercer and others (Series V), undated (Box 44, Folder 505)
  - Crump, Walter Gray (Series V), undated (Box 44, Folder 506)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. and others (Series V), circa 1940 (Box 44, Folder 507)
  - Lee, John C.H. and Jock Lawrence (Series V), 1944 February (Box 44, Folder 508)
  - Meany, George (Series V), undated (Box 44, Folder 509)
  - Reuther, Walter P. (Series V), undated (Box 44, Folder 510)
  - Wright, Louis Tompkins (Series V), undated (Box 44, Folder 511)
  - Unidentified (Series V), undated (Box 44, Folder 512)
  - Newspaper clipping regarding White's death and funeral, Chicago Defender (Series IV), 1955 April 2 (Box 46)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.83 linear feet (2 boxes)
  Boxes 39-40 contain fragile originals. The material is arranged in folder order and may only be seen with the permission of the appropriate curator. Preservation photocopies have been substituted in the main files for reference use.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 16, folder 151 (Box 39, Folder 393)
  - Box 16, folder 157 (Box 39, Folder 394)
  - Box 22, folder 193 (Box 39, Folder 395)
  - Box 23, folder 207 (Box 39, Folder 396)
  - Box 23, folder 208 (Box 39, Folder 397)
  - Box 23, folder 209 (Box 39, Folder 398)
  - Box 24, folder 235 (Box 39, Folder 399)
  - Box 25, folder 240 (Box 39, Folder 400)
  - Box 25, folder 241 (Box 39, Folder 401)
  - Box 25, folder 243 (Box 39, Folder 402)
  - Box 25, folder 245 (Box 39, Folder 403)
  - Box 25, folder 246 (Box 39, Folder 404)
  - Box 25, folder 249 (Box 39, Folder 405)
  - Box 25, folder 253 (Box 39, Folder 406)
  - Box 25, folder 255 (Box 39, Folder 407)
  - Box 25, folder 261 (Box 39, Folder 408)
  - Box 25, folder 263 (Box 39, Folder 409)
  - Box 26, folder 273 (Box 39, Folder 410)
  - Box 26, folder 274 (Box 39, Folder 411)
  - Box 26, folder 275 (Box 39, Folder 412)
  - Box 26, folder 276 (Box 39, Folder 413)
  - Box 26, folder 277 (Box 39, Folder 414)
  - Box 26, folder 281 (Box 39, Folder 415)
  - Box 29, folder 299 (Box 39, Folder 416)
  - Box 29, folder 300 (Box 39, Folder 417)
  - Box 29, folder 301 (Box 39, Folder 418)
  - Box 29, folder 306 (Box 39, Folder 419)
  - Box 29, folder 308 (Box 39, Folder 420)
  - Box 29, folder 309 (Box 39, Folder 421)
  - Box 30, folder 310 (Box 39, Folder 422)
  - Box 30, folder 311 (Box 39, Folder 423)
  - Box 30, folder 312 (Box 39, Folder 424)
  - Box 30, folder 313 (Box 39, Folder 425)
  - Box 30, folder 314 (Box 39, Folder 426)
  - Box 30, folder 315 (Box 40, Folder 427)
  - Box 30, folder 316 (Box 40, Folder 428)
  - Box 30, folder 317 (Box 40, Folder 429)
  - Box 31, folder 318 (Box 40, Folder 430)
  - Box 31, folder 319 (Box 40, Folder 431)
  - Box 31, folder 320 (Box 40, Folder 432)
  - Box 31, folder 322 (Box 40, Folder 433)
  - Box 32, folder 326 (Box 40, Folder 434)
  - Box 32, folder 328 (Box 40, Folder 435)
  - Box 32, folder 331 (Box 40, Folder 436)
  - Box 32, folder 332 (Box 40, Folder 437)
  - Box 32, folder 333 (Box 40, Folder 438)
  - Box 32, folder 337 (Box 40, Folder 439)
  - Box 32, folder 338 (Box 40, Folder 440)
  - Box 32, folder 339 (Box 40, Folder 441)
  - Box 32, folder 341 (Box 40, Folder 442)
  - Box 32, folder 342 (Box 40, Folder 443)
  - Box 33, folder 343 (Box 40, Folder 444)
  - Box 33, folder 344 (Box 40, Folder 445)
  - Box 33, folder 345 (Box 40, Folder 446)
  - Box 33, folder 348 (Box 40, Folder 447)
  - Box 33, folder 351 (Box 40, Folder 448)
  - Box 34, folder 358 (Box 40, Folder 449)